<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>aad on my tech ramblings</title>
    
    
    
    <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/tags/aad/</link>
    <description>Recent content in aad on my tech ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 10:21:33 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.mytechramblings.com/tags/aad/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Securing a graphQL API with Azure Active Directory</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/securing-dotnet-graphql-api-with-aad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 10:21:33 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/securing-dotnet-graphql-api-with-aad/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Just show me the code
As always if you don’t care about the post I have upload the source code on my Github.
 In today&amp;rsquo;s post I want to talk about how you can secure a .NET graphQL API using Azure Active Directory (AAD).
If you want to build a graphQL API in .NET right now, the most well-known options available are the graphQL.NET implementation (https://graphql-dotnet.github.io/) and the HotChocolate one (https://chillicream.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying to setup an Azure DevOps organization using Terraform</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/automate-azure-devops-setup-using-terraform/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 10:00:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/automate-azure-devops-setup-using-terraform/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Show me the code
If you don&amp;rsquo;t care about my writings I have upload the code on my Github
 On today&amp;rsquo;s post I want to try to automate the setup of an Azure DevOps organization using the Azure DevOps Terraform provider.
 You might also be interested in these post I wrote a few months ago about automating the AAD App Registration process using the Terraform Azure Active Directory provider.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Answering some basic questions about registering applications on Azure Active Directory</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/answering-basic-questions-about-aad-app-registrations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 10:00:50 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/answering-basic-questions-about-aad-app-registrations/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          These past years I worked with a few companies that uses Azure Active Directory to perform authentication and authorization on their line-of-business (LOB) applications and from time to time I get questions about how to register apps on AAD.
Those questions are always pretty similar and most of the time the problem lies in some misconception, so I thought it might be a good idea to try to answer some of them and at the same time write them down in this post.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying to automate Azure Active Directory App Registration process using Terraform</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/automate-azure-ad-app-registration-using-terraform/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 21:22:44 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/automate-azure-ad-app-registration-using-terraform/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          &amp;gt; Updated content:
I wrote the original post almost 6 months ago and since then the AAD Terraform provider has been updated several times.
When I wrote the post I used the version 0.11 and right now the provider is on version 1.1.1, that&amp;rsquo;s a considerable version bump so some people asked me if I could update this post.
Without further ado let&amp;rsquo;s rebuild this example using the 1.1.1 version.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>