<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on my tech ramblings</title>
    
    
    
    <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on my tech ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 10:01:37 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Profiling a .NET6 app running in a linux container with dotnet-trace, dotnet-dump, dotnet-counters, dotnet-gcdump and Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/profiling-a-net-app-with-dotnet-cli-diagnostic-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 10:01:37 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/profiling-a-net-app-with-dotnet-cli-diagnostic-tools/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          This post contains a few practical examples showing you how to profile a .NET6 application running in a linux container using the .NET CLI diagnostic tools (dotnet-trace, dotnet-dump, dotnet-counters and dotnet-gcdump) and Visual Studio.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with AWS Distro for OpenTelemetry and distributed tracing using .NET. Part 2: Building the demo</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/getting-started-with-aws-distro-for-otel-and-dotnet-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 10:00:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/getting-started-with-aws-distro-for-otel-and-dotnet-part-2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          This is a 2 part-series post. In part 2 I’ll show you how to build and configure properly a few distributed .NET apps that will send traces to the AWS OTEL Collector, and also how to analyze those traces in AWS X-Ray.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with AWS Distro for OpenTelemetry and distributed tracing using .NET. Part 1: Setting up the AWS OTEL Collector</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/getting-started-with-aws-distro-for-otel-and-dotnet-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 10:10:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/getting-started-with-aws-distro-for-otel-and-dotnet-part-1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          This is a 2 part-series post. In part 1 I’ll be talking about what is the AWS OpenTelemetry Collector and how to set it up for ingesting and exporting traces to AWS X-Ray.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building an Async HTTP Api with Azure Durable Functions and Python</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/building-an-async-http-api-with-durable-functions-and-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 11:20:04 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/building-an-async-http-api-with-durable-functions-and-python/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          The async HTTP API pattern addresses the problem of coordinating the state of long-running operations with external clients. Azure Durable Functions provides built-in support for this pattern and in this post I&#39;m going to show you how to implement it using Python.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing how to use some container vulnerabilities scanners with Azure Pipelines</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/testing-container-vulnerabilities-scanners-using-azure-pipelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 10:45:14 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/testing-container-vulnerabilities-scanners-using-azure-pipelines/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Vulnerability scanning allows us to review the security state of the container images and take actions to fix issues identified during the scan, resulting in more secure deployments. In this post I will be covering how you can use some of the most well-known scanners alongside with your Azure DevOps CI/CD YAML Pipelines.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up the SonarQube scanner when building a .NET Core container image</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/running-a-sonarqube-scan-when-building-docker-image/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 10:05:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/running-a-sonarqube-scan-when-building-docker-image/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          If you&#39;re using containers quite probably you&#39;re doing the build, test and analysis steps inside the Dockerfile, and setting up the SonarQube scanner when building the image can be a little more cumbersome than usual, and that&#39;s why I wanted to write a little bit about it.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Securing a graphQL API with Azure Active Directory</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/securing-dotnet-graphql-api-with-aad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 10:21:33 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/securing-dotnet-graphql-api-with-aad/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          In today&#39;s post I want to talk about how you can secure a .NET graphQL API that uses HotChocolate (https://chillicream.com/) with Azure Active Directory.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some common gotchas when trying to deploy a dotnet gRPC app to AWS ECS</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/some-gotchas-when-deploying-a-dotnet-grpc-app-to-ecs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 10:05:32 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/some-gotchas-when-deploying-a-dotnet-grpc-app-to-ecs/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Lately I&#39;ve been deploying a sizable amount of gRPC services to AWS ECS so I thought it might be useful to talk a little bit about some gotchas I have encountered. Some of the problems I&#39;ll be talking about on this post are specific of the .NET implementation of gRPC and another ones are from the AWS side.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to build a .NET template and use it within Visual Studio. Part 2: Creating a template package</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/create-dotnet-templates-for-visual-studio-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 10:01:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/create-dotnet-templates-for-visual-studio-part-2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          This is a 2 part-series post. In part 2 I&#39;ll show you how to convert a few .NET apps into .NET templates, package them together in a single NuGet pack and use them as templates within Visual Studio.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to build a .NET template and use it within Visual Studio. Part 1: Key concepts</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/create-dotnet-templates-for-visual-studio-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 00:07:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/create-dotnet-templates-for-visual-studio-part-1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          This is a 2 part-series post. In part 1 I&#39;ll be talking about a few key concepts that you should know when creating a .NET template.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4 ways to deploy a .NET Core Lambda using AWS CDK</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/deploy-dotnet-lambdas-with-aws-cdk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 10:01:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/deploy-dotnet-lambdas-with-aws-cdk/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          In today&#39;s post I want to show you 4 available options for deploying a .NET Core lambda with AWS CDK.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with OpenTelemetry and distributed tracing in .NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/getting-started-with-opentelemetry-and-dotnet-core/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 10:11:51 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/getting-started-with-opentelemetry-and-dotnet-core/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          OpenTelemetry is a set of APIs, SDKs, tooling and integrations that are designed for the creation and management of telemetry data such as traces, metrics, and logs. On today&#39;s post I&#39;m going to show you how you can start using OTEL and distributed tracing with .NET Core.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying to setup an Azure DevOps organization using Terraform</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/automate-azure-devops-setup-using-terraform/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 10:00:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/automate-azure-devops-setup-using-terraform/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          On today&#39;s post I want to test the Azure DevOps Terraform provider and that&#39;s why I&#39;ll be trying to automate the setup of an Azure DevOps organization using it.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to configure your custom roslyn analyzer using an .editorconfig file</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/configure-roslyn-analyzers-using-editorconfig/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 12:59:43 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/configure-roslyn-analyzers-using-editorconfig/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Roslyn Analyzers are extensions that analyze source code and report violations. Some analyzers are built-into VS and some are third party ones which can be installed (like StyleCopyAnalyzers, FxCopAnalyzers, etc.). On today&#39;s post I will show you how you can configure your custom roslyn analyzers with an .editorconfig file.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing out the Azure Static Web Apps service. Let&#39;s try to deploy this blog into an static web app</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/moving-this-blog-to-azure-static-webapps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 10:04:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/moving-this-blog-to-azure-static-webapps/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          I been wanting to try Azure Static Web Apps for quite some time and I thought that instead of deploying some dummy static site I could use my blog as a test subject, so let&#39;s do it!
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An opinionated approach about how to create an AWS ECS Fargate cluster and deploy apps on it using Azure DevOps Pipelines</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/create-an-ecs-cluster-and-deploy-apps-using-azure-devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 10:10:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/create-an-ecs-cluster-and-deploy-apps-using-azure-devops/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          These past couple of weeks I&#39;ve been tinkering with AWS ECS Fargate and after losing some time tackling different approaches I thought it might be useful to write down what I ended up building, so without further ado let&#39;s dig in.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Answering some basic questions about registering applications on Azure Active Directory</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/answering-basic-questions-about-aad-app-registrations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 10:00:50 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/answering-basic-questions-about-aad-app-registrations/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          These past years I worked with a few companies that uses Azure Active Directory to perform authentication and authorization on their line-of-business (LOB) applications and from time to time I get questions about how to register apps on AAD. Those questions are always pretty similar and most of the time the problem lies in some misconception, so I thought it might be a good idea to try to answer some of them and at the same time write them down in this post.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Provisioning resources on AWS using AWS CDK and Azure DevOps Pipelines</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/provisioning-aws-resources-using-cdk-azure-devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 10:02:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/provisioning-aws-resources-using-cdk-azure-devops/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          In today&#39;s post I will show you how you can deploy an AWS CDK application using Azure DevOps.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to centrally manage NuGet package versions within your solution</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/centrally-manage-nuget-versions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 10:01:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/centrally-manage-nuget-versions/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          In this post I want to show you some of the different options available when you want to centrally manage NuGet versions within a solution.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A practical example of GitOps using Azure DevOps, Azure Container Registry, Helm, Flux and Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/gitops-with-azure-devops-helm-acr-flux-and-k8s/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 22:10:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/gitops-with-azure-devops-helm-acr-flux-and-k8s/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          GitOps is a way of implementing Continuous Deployment. The core idea of GitOps is having a Git repository that always contains declarative descriptions of the desired infrastructure, and in this post I&#39;ll be building a practical example of GitOps using Azure.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying to automate Azure Active Directory App Registration process using Terraform</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/automate-azure-ad-app-registration-using-terraform/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 21:22:44 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/automate-azure-ad-app-registration-using-terraform/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Today I want to try to use Terraform to automate the app registration process in Azure Active Directory.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to restore nuget packages from an Azure DevOps Private Feed when building a Docker image</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/how-to-use-a-private-nuget-feed-with-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 19:12:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/how-to-use-a-private-nuget-feed-with-docker/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          In this post I&#39;ll show you how to restore NuGet packages from an Azure DevOps private feed when building a Docker image.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why and how you should add a healthcheck endpoint to your Wcf legacy applications</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/how-to-add-healthchecks-to-wcf-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 17:30:06 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/how-to-add-healthchecks-to-wcf-apps/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          What I wanted to talk in these post is how easy is to add a healthcheck endpoint in a WCF application, and how you can use it in case you want to move the application into the Cloud in the near future.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enforce the use of a specific .NET Core version using Roslyn</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/enforce-your-dotnet-apps-framework-version-using-roslyn-analyzers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 15:25:42 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/enforce-your-dotnet-apps-framework-version-using-roslyn-analyzers/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          In these past few years Microsoft has kept a steady flow of new .NET Core versions, and if you have hundreds of applications in your company it&#39;s almost impossible to keep them updated to the most recent version of the framework. If you want to enforce that everyone on your company is using the correct framework version when they create a new application you can use a Roslyn Analyzer.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create and host a blog with Hugo and GitHub Pages in less than 30 minutes</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/create-a-website-with-hugo-and-gh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 18:28:38 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/create-a-website-with-hugo-and-gh/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Do you want to start a blog and don&#39;t want to lose a lot of time setting everything up?  That exactly why I&#39;m going to show you how to build a blog site with Hugo and GitHub Pages.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>