<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on my tech ramblings</title>
    
    
    
    <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on my tech ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 10:04:40 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing out Azure Static Web Apps service. Let&#39;s try to deploy this blog into an static web app</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/moving-this-blog-to-azure-static-webapps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 10:04:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/moving-this-blog-to-azure-static-webapps/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          If you only care about the end result, I upload the final result in this GitHub repository: github-link
This repository contains the entire blog source code.
In the &amp;quot;/infrastructure&amp;quot; folder you can find an ARM template that is used to create the static web app.
In the /.github/workflows folder you can find a couple of github actions:
 The infrastructure.yml file is a github action that creates the resources on Azure.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An opinionated approach about how to create an AWS ECS Fargate cluster and deploy apps on it using Azure DevOps Pipelines</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/create-an-ecs-cluster-and-deploy-apps-using-azure-devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 10:10:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/create-an-ecs-cluster-and-deploy-apps-using-azure-devops/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          These past couple of weeks I&amp;rsquo;ve been tinkering with AWS ECS Fargate and after losing some time tackling different approaches I thought it might be useful to write down what I ended up building.
My goal was trying to build an AWS ECS Fargate cluster and deploy apps on it using Azure DevOps Pipelines and I had 3 clear objectives I wanted to achieve.
 All the infrastructure in AWS must be created using IaC (infrastructure-as-code) and must be created using an Azure DevOps pipeline.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Answering some basic questions about registering applications on Azure Active Directory</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/answering-basic-questions-about-aad-app-registrations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 10:00:50 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/answering-basic-questions-about-aad-app-registrations/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          These past years I worked with a few companies that uses Azure Active Directory to perform authentication and authorization on their line-of-business (LOB) applications and from time to time I get questions about how to register apps on AAD.
Those questions are always pretty similar and most of the time the problem lies in some misconception, so I thought it might be a good idea to try to answer some of them and at the same time write them down in this post.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Provisioning resources on AWS using AWS CDK and Azure DevOps Pipelines</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/provisioning-aws-resources-using-cdk-azure-devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 10:02:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/provisioning-aws-resources-using-cdk-azure-devops/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Introduction First of all let me tell you that I&amp;rsquo;m huge proponent of Terraform as a framework for defining infrastructure in code. One of the things that I like most about Terraform is that not only every major cloud provider (AWS, Azure, GCP) offers their own provider but each day more and more companies are starting to offer their own Terraform providers, and those are great news because with Terraform I can create almost any cloud infrastructure that I want and also a huge array of varied resources such as: VMware vSphere Virtual Machines, RabbitMq Queues, Grafana dashboards amongst many many others.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to centrally manage NuGet package versions within your solution</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/centrally-manage-nuget-versions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 10:01:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/centrally-manage-nuget-versions/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          A pretty common scenario in complex .NET applications is having them splitted in multiple csharp projects inside a single solution, even with the proliferation of microservices is pretty common seeing the client and the business logic decoupled in multiple projects inside a single solution.
And that behaviour is even more common if you&amp;rsquo;re using some kind of software architecture like &amp;ldquo;Domain Driven Design&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Hexagonal Architecture&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Clean Architecture&amp;rdquo;.
A common problem that usually appears when the number of projects begins to pile up inside a single solution is mantaining consistency between nuget versions, and quite some times you end up with every project using a different version of the same package.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A practical example of GitOps using Azure DevOps, Azure Container Registry, Helm, Flux and Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/gitops-with-azure-devops-helm-acr-flux-and-k8s/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 22:10:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/gitops-with-azure-devops-helm-acr-flux-and-k8s/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          GitOps is a term introduced by WeaveWorks a few years ago (https://www.weave.works/blog/gitops-operations-by-pull-request)
GitOps is a way of implementing Continuous Deployment. The core idea of GitOps is having a Git repository that always contains declarative descriptions of the infrastructure currently desired in the production environment and an automated process to make the production environment match the described state in the repository.
If you want to deploy a new application or update an existing one, you only need to update the repository - the automated process handles everything else.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying to automate Azure Active Directory App Registration process using Terraform</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/automate-azure-ad-app-registration-using-terraform/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 21:22:44 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/automate-azure-ad-app-registration-using-terraform/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          &amp;gt; Updated content:
I wrote the original post almost 6 months ago and since then the AAD Terraform provider has been updated several times.
When I wrote the post I used the version 0.11 and right now the provider is on version 1.1.1, that&amp;rsquo;s a considerable version bump so some people asked me if I could update this post.
Without further ado let&amp;rsquo;s rebuild this example using the 1.1.1 version.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to restore nuget packages from an Azure DevOps Private Feed when building a Docker image</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/how-to-use-a-private-nuget-feed-with-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 19:12:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/how-to-use-a-private-nuget-feed-with-docker/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Let&amp;rsquo;s go for a quick post this time.
Imagine you&amp;rsquo;re trying to create a Docker image from an application and it is using some custom nugets. Those custom nugets are hosted in your private Azure DevOps Feed. And when you try to build the image you get one of the following errors:
/src/MyConsoleApplication.csproj : error NU1101: Unable to find package MyOwn.EmailService. No packages exist with this id in source(s): nuget.org Failed to restore /src/MyConsoleApplication.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why and how you should add a healthcheck endpoint to your Wcf legacy applications</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/how-to-add-healthchecks-to-wcf-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 17:30:06 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/how-to-add-healthchecks-to-wcf-apps/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Nowadays no one on his right mind is going to create a WCF from scratch. It really makes no sense to do it. It&amp;rsquo;s a deprecated technology, it does not work with .NET Core, only works on Windows OS and personally I found the configuration confusing as hell, every time I need to modify an existing one I have to spend a good amount of time trying to figure out what everything means.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enforce the use of a specific .NET Core version using Roslyn</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/enforce-your-dotnet-apps-framework-version-using-roslyn-analyzers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 15:25:42 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/enforce-your-dotnet-apps-framework-version-using-roslyn-analyzers/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          In these past few years Microsoft has kept a steady flow of new .NET Core versions: .NET Core 1.0, 1.1, 2.0, 2.1, 2.2 and so on and so forth.
If you have hundreds of applications in your company, it&amp;rsquo;s almost impossible to keep them updated to the most recent version of the framework, so most probably you&amp;rsquo;re going to end up having multiple versions running at the same time.
When trying to choose which versions are you going to support in your company a factor to consider is that only a few of those versions are long-time support (LTS).
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create and host a blog with Hugo and GitHub Pages in less than 30 minutes</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/create-a-website-with-hugo-and-gh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 18:28:38 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/create-a-website-with-hugo-and-gh/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Do you want to start a blog and don&amp;rsquo;t want to lose a lot of time setting everything up?
That was exactly my thought! I wanted to build a blog to write about my ramblings, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to spend long hours settings things up.
After doing a little of research about what options are available nowadays I found that Hugo could be a good fit.
What&amp;rsquo;s Hugo? Hugo is a static HTML and CSS website generator, it is written in Golang and it relies on markdown files and I like how few steps you need to do to have a site ready to rock.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>