<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on my tech ramblings</title>
    
    
    
    <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on my tech ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:10:55 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with OpenTelemetry Metrics in .NET 8. Part 2: Instrumenting the BookStore API</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/getting-started-with-opentelemetry-metrics-and-dotnet-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:10:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/getting-started-with-opentelemetry-metrics-and-dotnet-part-2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          In this two-part series, I’m going to show you how to use OpenTelemetry to generate custom metrics and how to visualize those metrics using Prometheus and Grafana. In part 2, I’ll demonstrate how to add OpenTelemetry Metrics to a real life .NET 8 app and how to visualize those metrics using Prometheus and Grafana.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with OpenTelemetry Metrics in .NET 8. Part 1: Key concepts</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/getting-started-with-opentelemetry-metrics-and-dotnet-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:00:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/getting-started-with-opentelemetry-metrics-and-dotnet-part-1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          In this two-part series, I’m going to show you how to use OpenTelemetry to generate custom metrics and how to visualize those metrics using Prometheus and Grafana. In part 1, I’ll be discussing some key concepts that you should know when using OpenTelemetry Metrics with dotnet.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying to automate Microsoft Entra ID App Registration process using Terraform</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/automate-entra-app-registration-process-using-terraform/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 10:00:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/automate-entra-app-registration-process-using-terraform/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          The purpose of this post is to test the App Registration process using the latest version of the Terraform provider for Microsoft Entra ID. To achieve this, we&#39;re going to register multiple apps on Microsoft Entra ID and make them interact with each other using a couple of different OAuth2 authorization flows.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyze Polly Telemetry using Prometheus, Grafana and OpenTelemetry Metrics</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/analyze-polly-telemetry-using-otel-metrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 10:00:43 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/analyze-polly-telemetry-using-otel-metrics/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Starting with version 8, Polly provides Telemetry for all built-in strategies. This post will show you how you can send this Telemetry to Prometheus and Grafana for a more in-depth analysis using OpenTelemetry Metrics.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Q&amp;A app capable of answering questions related to your enterprise documents using AWS Bedrock, AWS Kendra, AWS S3 and Streamlit</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/building-qa-app-with-aws-bedrock-kendra-s3-and-streamlit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 10:00:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/building-qa-app-with-aws-bedrock-kendra-s3-and-streamlit/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          The purpose of this post is to demonstrate how easy is to build a basic Q&amp;A app capable of answering questions about your company&#39;s internal documents. This time, we will use only AWS services to build it (plus Streamlit for the user interface).
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with OpenTelemetry and distributed tracing in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/getting-started-with-opentelemetry-and-dotnet-core/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 12:41:51 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/getting-started-with-opentelemetry-and-dotnet-core/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          OpenTelemetry is a set of APIs, SDKs, tooling and integrations that are designed for the creation and management of telemetry data such as traces, metrics, and logs. On today&#39;s post I&#39;m going to show you how you can start using OTEL and distributed tracing with .NET.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back to .NET basics: How to easily build a Strategy pattern using dependency injection</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/dotnet-strategy-pattern-using-dependency-injection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2023 10:01:54 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/dotnet-strategy-pattern-using-dependency-injection/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          In this very brief post, we will see how easy is to build a Strategy pattern in .NET when using dependency injection.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back to .NET basics: How to properly use HttpClient</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/dotnet-httpclient-basic-usage-scenarios/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2023 10:21:52 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/dotnet-httpclient-basic-usage-scenarios/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          In this post, we will explore a few common scenarios where HttpClient is employed. For each scenario, we will discuss the reasons behind its proper or improper usage, using the help of the netstat command.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a C# enhancing app using Azure OpenAI GPT-4 and Streamlit</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/building-a-csharp-enhancing-app-using-openai-gpt4-and-streamlit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 10:00:01 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/building-a-csharp-enhancing-app-using-openai-gpt4-and-streamlit/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          This post demonstrates the simplicity of developing an app that can enhances a C# file using only GenAI&#39;s basic skills. By utilizing Azure OpenAI GPT-4 model, the app can effortlessly add or improve XML comments, provide code explanations, suggest enhancements, and generate unit tests for any given C# file.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing Chiseled Ubuntu container images with .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/testing-chiseled-ubuntu-containers-with-dotnet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 10:03:07 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/testing-chiseled-ubuntu-containers-with-dotnet/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          The objective of this post is to test Ubuntu Chiseled images in combination with .NET, evaluating whether it is truly worthwhile to migrate our .NET apps to utilize these base images or not.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Q&amp;A app capable of answering questions related to your enterprise documents using Azure OpenAI&#39;s GPT-4, Pinecone and Streamlit.</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/building-qa-app-with-openai-pinecone-and-streamlit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 10:03:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/building-qa-app-with-openai-pinecone-and-streamlit/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          The purpose of this post is to show you how to build a basic GPT-4 Q&amp;A app in just a couple of hours that is capable of answering questions about your company&#39;s internal documents. We will use Azure OpenAI, Pinecone and Streamlit to build it.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a serverless API that tweets about my blog posts using Azure OpenAI and LangChain</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/build-an-api-that-tweets-using-azure-openai-and-langchain/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 10:01:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/build-an-api-that-tweets-using-azure-openai-and-langchain/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          This post is going to show you a simple way of building a serverless Python API that uses LangChain and Azure OpenAI to create tweets summarizing the content of my blog posts.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to integrate your Roslyn Analyzer project with SonarQube</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/how-to-integrate-your-roslyn-analyzers-with-sonarqube/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 10:55:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/how-to-integrate-your-roslyn-analyzers-with-sonarqube/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Right now there are 2 ways to add rules from a Roslyn Analyzer project into SonarQube. In this post I want to show you how both options work and also what&#39;re the pros and cons of one over the other.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 ways to deploy a .NET Lambda using AWS CDK</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/deploy-dotnet-lambdas-with-aws-cdk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 10:01:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/deploy-dotnet-lambdas-with-aws-cdk/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          This post is going to walk you through 5 different ways to deploy a .NET lambda using AWS CDK.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to modernize a legacy .NET Framework WCF app using CoreWCF and .NET 7</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/modernize-wcf-legacy-app-using-corewcf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 10:01:16 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/modernize-wcf-legacy-app-using-corewcf/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          CoreWCF is a port of the Windows Communication Foundation (WCF) framework to the latest .NET version. The main goal of the CoreWCF project is to enable existing WCF services to be moved to .NET 7. In this post I&#39;ll show you step by step how easy (or hard) is the process of migrating an existing .NET 4.7 WCF app to .NET 7 using the CoreWCF project.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to automatically purge stale images from Azure Container Registry using ACR Tasks</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/automatically-purge-acr-images-using-acr-tasks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2022 13:03:19 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/automatically-purge-acr-images-using-acr-tasks/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Keeping your container registry free of stale or unwanted images is a task that often gets overlooked when beginning working with containers in the enterprise. In this post, I want to show you how you can use ACR Tasks to automate this process when working with Azure Container Registry.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying out the built-in container support for the .NET SDK</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/trying-out-the-built-in-container-support-for-the-dotnet-7-sdk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 10:01:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/trying-out-the-built-in-container-support-for-the-dotnet-7-sdk/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          A few months ago the built-in container support for the .NET SDK was announced. In this post I&#39;ll put this feature to test, I&#39;ll try to migrate from an application that contains a rather complex Dockerfile to a new version that has no Dockerfile and instead uses the container support feature.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to deploy an Azure resource using Terraform when it is not available in the AzureRM official provider</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/deploy-az-resources-when-not-available-on-azurerm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 10:30:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/deploy-az-resources-when-not-available-on-azurerm/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          This post is going to walk you through the options available when we want to create or update a service on Azure using Terraform, but it is not available on the AzureRM Terraform provider.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to notify AWS events to Microsoft Teams using AWS EventBridge and AWS Lambda</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/notify-aws-events-to-microsoft-teams/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 10:01:12 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/notify-aws-events-to-microsoft-teams/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          An AWS event indicates a change in a service, and in this post I want to show you how you can notify those events to a Microsoft Teams channel using AWS EventBridge and AWS Lambda.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keep your .NET platform images up to date using AWS ECR and Azure Pipelines</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/keep-your-platform-images-updated-when-using-aws-ecr-with-azure-pipelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 11:06:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/keep-your-platform-images-updated-when-using-aws-ecr-with-azure-pipelines/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          When talking about containers security on the enterprise one of the best practices is to use your own platform images, those platform images are the base for your company applications. In this post I&#39;m going to show you an opinionated implementation of how to automate the creation and update of your own .NET platform images using Azure Pipelines and AWS ECR.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to easily check on your CI/CD pipelines if your app has a NuGet package with a security vulnerability</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/check-if-your-dotnet-app-dependencies-has-a-security-vulnerability-on-you-cicd-pipelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 10:01:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/check-if-your-dotnet-app-dependencies-has-a-security-vulnerability-on-you-cicd-pipelines/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Almost any dotnet application has several NuGet dependencies, and those dependencies may have their own dependencies, and so on and so forth. What if any of those dependencies you&#39;re using contains a security vulnerability? You can check on your CI/CD pipeline if your application has any known NuGet vulnerability with just a couple of lines of bash script.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to deploy a SignalR Core application to AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/deploying-a-signalr-core-app-on-aws/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 10:00:40 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/deploying-a-signalr-core-app-on-aws/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          This post is about which AWS services can be used and how to set them up properly when you want to deploy a SignalR Core application to AWS.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing Azure Private Endpoints DNS resolution over an Azure P2S VPN connection</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/testing-private-dns-resolution-over-a-p2s-vpn-using-azure-dns-private-resolver/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 10:10:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/testing-private-dns-resolution-over-a-p2s-vpn-using-azure-dns-private-resolver/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          The purpose of this post is to try out the new Azure DNS Private Resolver resource. To test it, we&#39;re going to try to solve one of the current issues that Azure VPN has right now: when connected over an Azure P2S VPN the private DNS zone resolution does not work. This becomes quite problematic when you&#39;re using private endpoints to secure some private resources, because there is no easy way to resolve the private endpoint DNS when connected to a P2S VPN.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linting a .NET 6 app Dockerfile using Hadolint, dockerfile_lint and Azure Pipelines</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/linting-a-dotnet-app-dockerfile-using-hadolint-dockerfile-lint-and-azure-pipelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 10:05:01 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/linting-a-dotnet-app-dockerfile-using-hadolint-dockerfile-lint-and-azure-pipelines/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Like any other language, Dockerfiles can and should be linted for updated best practices and code quality checks. In this post I will show you how to incorporate a couple of Dockerfile linters into our Secure DevOps workflow to ensure our Dockerfiles are always readable, understandable and maintainable.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to bootstrap Terraform and Azure DevOps to start deploying your infrastructure as code to Azure</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/how-to-bootstrap-terraform-and-azdo-to-start-deploying-iac-to-azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 12:30:10 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/how-to-bootstrap-terraform-and-azdo-to-start-deploying-iac-to-azure/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Deploying infrastructure as code on Azure using Azure Pipelines and Terraform requires a minimal bootstrap process. This process can be done manually, but you&#39;ll have to do it every time you want to start deploying resources into a new subscription. So, having some kind of automation seems the way to go here. And that&#39;s exactly what I want to show in this post, how to programmatically bootstrap an Azure subscription and an Azure DevOps project to start deploying Infrastructure as Code with Terraform.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Profiling a .NET6 app running on AWS ECS Fargate with dotnet-monitor</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/profiling-a-net-app-on-aws-ecs-fargate-with-dotnet-monitor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 10:25:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/profiling-a-net-app-on-aws-ecs-fargate-with-dotnet-monitor/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          The dotnet-monitor tool is an alternative to the .NET CLI diagnostic tools. In this post I&#39;ll show you how to deploy a .NET 6 application into AWS ECS Fargate with dotnet-monitor as a sidecar container, and afterwards how you can profile an app using the dotnet-monitor HTTP API.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Profiling a .NET6 app running in a linux container with dotnet-trace, dotnet-dump, dotnet-counters, dotnet-gcdump and Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/profiling-a-net-app-with-dotnet-cli-diagnostic-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 10:01:37 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/profiling-a-net-app-with-dotnet-cli-diagnostic-tools/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          This post contains a few practical examples showing you how to profile a .NET6 application running in a linux container using the .NET CLI diagnostic tools (dotnet-trace, dotnet-dump, dotnet-counters and dotnet-gcdump) and Visual Studio.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with AWS Distro for OpenTelemetry and distributed tracing using .NET. Part 2: Building the demo</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/getting-started-with-aws-distro-for-otel-and-dotnet-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 10:00:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/getting-started-with-aws-distro-for-otel-and-dotnet-part-2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          This is a 2 part-series post. In part 2 I’ll show you how to build and configure properly a few distributed .NET apps that will send traces to the AWS OTEL Collector, and also how to analyze those traces in AWS X-Ray.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with AWS Distro for OpenTelemetry and distributed tracing using .NET. Part 1: Setting up the AWS OTEL Collector</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/getting-started-with-aws-distro-for-otel-and-dotnet-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 10:10:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/getting-started-with-aws-distro-for-otel-and-dotnet-part-1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          This is a 2 part-series post. In part 1 I’ll be talking about what is the AWS OpenTelemetry Collector and how to set it up for ingesting and exporting traces to AWS X-Ray.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building an Async HTTP Api with Azure Durable Functions and Python</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/building-an-async-http-api-with-durable-functions-and-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 11:20:04 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/building-an-async-http-api-with-durable-functions-and-python/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          The async HTTP API pattern addresses the problem of coordinating the state of long-running operations with external clients. Azure Durable Functions provides built-in support for this pattern and in this post I&#39;m going to show you how to implement it using Python.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing how to use some container vulnerabilities scanners with Azure Pipelines</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/testing-container-vulnerabilities-scanners-using-azure-pipelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 10:45:14 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/testing-container-vulnerabilities-scanners-using-azure-pipelines/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Vulnerability scanning allows us to review the security state of the container images and take actions to fix issues identified during the scan, resulting in more secure deployments. In this post I will be covering how you can use some of the most well-known scanners alongside with your Azure DevOps CI/CD YAML Pipelines.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up the SonarQube scanner when building a .NET Core container image</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/running-a-sonarqube-scan-when-building-docker-image/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 10:05:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/running-a-sonarqube-scan-when-building-docker-image/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          If you&#39;re using containers quite probably you&#39;re doing the build, test and analysis steps inside the Dockerfile, and setting up the SonarQube scanner when building the image can be a little more cumbersome than usual, and that&#39;s why I wanted to write a little bit about it.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Securing a graphQL API with Azure Active Directory</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/securing-dotnet-graphql-api-with-aad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 10:21:33 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/securing-dotnet-graphql-api-with-aad/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          In today&#39;s post I want to talk about how you can secure a .NET graphQL API that uses HotChocolate (https://chillicream.com/) with Azure Active Directory.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some common gotchas when trying to deploy a dotnet gRPC app to AWS ECS</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/some-gotchas-when-deploying-a-dotnet-grpc-app-to-ecs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 10:05:32 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/some-gotchas-when-deploying-a-dotnet-grpc-app-to-ecs/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Lately I&#39;ve been deploying a sizable amount of gRPC services to AWS ECS so I thought it might be useful to talk a little bit about some gotchas I have encountered. Some of the problems I&#39;ll be talking about on this post are specific of the .NET implementation of gRPC and another ones are from the AWS side.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to build a .NET template and use it within Visual Studio. Part 2: Creating a template package</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/create-dotnet-templates-for-visual-studio-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 10:01:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/create-dotnet-templates-for-visual-studio-part-2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          This is a 2 part-series post. In part 2 I&#39;ll show you how to convert a few .NET apps into .NET templates, package them together in a single NuGet pack and use them as templates within Visual Studio.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to build a .NET template and use it within Visual Studio. Part 1: Key concepts</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/create-dotnet-templates-for-visual-studio-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 00:07:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/create-dotnet-templates-for-visual-studio-part-1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          This is a 2 part-series post. In part 1 I&#39;ll be talking about a few key concepts that you should know when creating a .NET template.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying to setup an Azure DevOps organization using Terraform</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/automate-azure-devops-setup-using-terraform/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 10:00:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/automate-azure-devops-setup-using-terraform/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          On today&#39;s post I want to test the Azure DevOps Terraform provider and that&#39;s why I&#39;ll be trying to automate the setup of an Azure DevOps organization using it.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to configure your custom roslyn analyzer using an .editorconfig file</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/configure-roslyn-analyzers-using-editorconfig/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 12:59:43 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/configure-roslyn-analyzers-using-editorconfig/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Roslyn Analyzers are extensions that analyze source code and report violations. Some analyzers are built-into VS and some are third party ones which can be installed (like StyleCopyAnalyzers, FxCopAnalyzers, etc.). On today&#39;s post I will show you how you can configure your custom roslyn analyzers with an .editorconfig file.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing out the Azure Static Web Apps service. Let&#39;s try to deploy this blog into an static web app</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/moving-this-blog-to-azure-static-webapps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 10:04:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/moving-this-blog-to-azure-static-webapps/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          I been wanting to try Azure Static Web Apps for quite some time and I thought that instead of deploying some dummy static site I could use my blog as a test subject, so let&#39;s do it!
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An opinionated approach about how to create an AWS ECS Fargate cluster and deploy apps on it using Azure DevOps Pipelines</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/create-an-ecs-cluster-and-deploy-apps-using-azure-devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 10:10:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/create-an-ecs-cluster-and-deploy-apps-using-azure-devops/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          These past couple of weeks I&#39;ve been tinkering with AWS ECS Fargate and after losing some time tackling different approaches I thought it might be useful to write down what I ended up building, so without further ado let&#39;s dig in.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Answering some basic questions about registering applications on Azure Active Directory</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/answering-basic-questions-about-aad-app-registrations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 10:00:50 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/answering-basic-questions-about-aad-app-registrations/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          These past years I worked with a few companies that uses Azure Active Directory to perform authentication and authorization on their line-of-business (LOB) applications and from time to time I get questions about how to register apps on AAD. Those questions are always pretty similar and most of the time the problem lies in some misconception, so I thought it might be a good idea to try to answer some of them and at the same time write them down in this post.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Provisioning resources on AWS using AWS CDK and Azure DevOps Pipelines</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/provisioning-aws-resources-using-cdk-azure-devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 10:02:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/provisioning-aws-resources-using-cdk-azure-devops/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          In today&#39;s post I will show you how you can deploy an AWS CDK application using Azure DevOps.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to centrally manage NuGet package versions within your solution</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/centrally-manage-nuget-versions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 10:01:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/centrally-manage-nuget-versions/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          In this post I want to show you some of the different options available when you want to centrally manage NuGet versions within a solution.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A practical example of GitOps using Azure DevOps, Azure Container Registry, Helm, Flux and Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/gitops-with-azure-devops-helm-acr-flux-and-k8s/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 22:10:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/gitops-with-azure-devops-helm-acr-flux-and-k8s/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          GitOps is a way of implementing Continuous Deployment. The core idea of GitOps is having a Git repository that always contains declarative descriptions of the desired infrastructure, and in this post I&#39;ll be building a practical example of GitOps using Azure.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying to automate Azure Active Directory App Registration process using Terraform</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/automate-azure-ad-app-registration-using-terraform/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 21:22:44 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/automate-azure-ad-app-registration-using-terraform/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Today I want to try to use Terraform to automate the app registration process in Azure Active Directory.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to restore nuget packages from an Azure DevOps Private Feed when building a Docker image</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/how-to-use-a-private-nuget-feed-with-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 19:12:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/how-to-use-a-private-nuget-feed-with-docker/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          In this post I&#39;ll show you how to restore NuGet packages from an Azure DevOps private feed when building a Docker image.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why and how you should add a healthcheck endpoint to your Wcf legacy applications</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/how-to-add-healthchecks-to-wcf-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 17:30:06 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/how-to-add-healthchecks-to-wcf-apps/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          What I wanted to talk in these post is how easy is to add a healthcheck endpoint in a WCF application, and how you can use it in case you want to move the application into the Cloud in the near future.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enforce the use of a specific .NET Core version using Roslyn</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/enforce-your-dotnet-apps-framework-version-using-roslyn-analyzers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 15:25:42 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/enforce-your-dotnet-apps-framework-version-using-roslyn-analyzers/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          In these past few years Microsoft has kept a steady flow of new .NET Core versions, and if you have hundreds of applications in your company it&#39;s almost impossible to keep them updated to the most recent version of the framework. If you want to enforce that everyone on your company is using the correct framework version when they create a new application you can use a Roslyn Analyzer.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create and host a blog with Hugo and GitHub Pages in less than 30 minutes</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/create-a-website-with-hugo-and-gh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 18:28:38 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/create-a-website-with-hugo-and-gh/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Do you want to start a blog and don&#39;t want to lose a lot of time setting everything up?  That exactly why I&#39;m going to show you how to build a blog site with Hugo and GitHub Pages.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>