<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>azure on my tech ramblings</title>
    
    
    
    <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/tags/azure/</link>
    <description>Recent content in azure on my tech ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 10:45:14 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.mytechramblings.com/tags/azure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing how to use some container vulnerabilities scanners with Azure Pipelines</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/testing-container-vulnerabilities-scanners-using-azure-pipelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 10:45:14 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/testing-container-vulnerabilities-scanners-using-azure-pipelines/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Vulnerability scanning allows us to review the security state of the container images and take actions to fix issues identified during the scan, resulting in more secure deployments. In this post I will be covering how you can use some of the most well-known scanners alongside with your Azure DevOps CI/CD YAML Pipelines.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Securing a graphQL API with Azure Active Directory</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/securing-dotnet-graphql-api-with-aad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 10:21:33 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/securing-dotnet-graphql-api-with-aad/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          In today&#39;s post I want to talk about how you can secure a .NET graphQL API that uses HotChocolate (https://chillicream.com/) with Azure Active Directory.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying to setup an Azure DevOps organization using Terraform</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/automate-azure-devops-setup-using-terraform/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 10:00:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/automate-azure-devops-setup-using-terraform/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          On today&#39;s post I want to test the Azure DevOps Terraform provider and that&#39;s why I&#39;ll be trying to automate the setup of an Azure DevOps organization using it.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing out the Azure Static Web Apps service. Let&#39;s try to deploy this blog into an static web app</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/moving-this-blog-to-azure-static-webapps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 10:04:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/moving-this-blog-to-azure-static-webapps/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          I been wanting to try Azure Static Web Apps for quite some time and I thought that instead of deploying some dummy static site I could use my blog as a test subject, so let&#39;s do it!
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An opinionated approach about how to create an AWS ECS Fargate cluster and deploy apps on it using Azure DevOps Pipelines</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/create-an-ecs-cluster-and-deploy-apps-using-azure-devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 10:10:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/create-an-ecs-cluster-and-deploy-apps-using-azure-devops/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          These past couple of weeks I&#39;ve been tinkering with AWS ECS Fargate and after losing some time tackling different approaches I thought it might be useful to write down what I ended up building, so without further ado let&#39;s dig in.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Answering some basic questions about registering applications on Azure Active Directory</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/answering-basic-questions-about-aad-app-registrations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 10:00:50 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/answering-basic-questions-about-aad-app-registrations/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          These past years I worked with a few companies that uses Azure Active Directory to perform authentication and authorization on their line-of-business (LOB) applications and from time to time I get questions about how to register apps on AAD. Those questions are always pretty similar and most of the time the problem lies in some misconception, so I thought it might be a good idea to try to answer some of them and at the same time write them down in this post.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Provisioning resources on AWS using AWS CDK and Azure DevOps Pipelines</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/provisioning-aws-resources-using-cdk-azure-devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 10:02:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/provisioning-aws-resources-using-cdk-azure-devops/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          In today&#39;s post I will show you how you can deploy an AWS CDK application using Azure DevOps.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A practical example of GitOps using Azure DevOps, Azure Container Registry, Helm, Flux and Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/gitops-with-azure-devops-helm-acr-flux-and-k8s/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 22:10:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/gitops-with-azure-devops-helm-acr-flux-and-k8s/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          GitOps is a way of implementing Continuous Deployment. The core idea of GitOps is having a Git repository that always contains declarative descriptions of the desired infrastructure, and in this post I&#39;ll be building a practical example of GitOps using Azure.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying to automate Azure Active Directory App Registration process using Terraform</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/automate-azure-ad-app-registration-using-terraform/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 21:22:44 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/automate-azure-ad-app-registration-using-terraform/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Today I want to try to use Terraform to automate the app registration process in Azure Active Directory.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why and how you should add a healthcheck endpoint to your Wcf legacy applications</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/how-to-add-healthchecks-to-wcf-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 17:30:06 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/how-to-add-healthchecks-to-wcf-apps/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          What I wanted to talk in these post is how easy is to add a healthcheck endpoint in a WCF application, and how you can use it in case you want to move the application into the Cloud in the near future.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>