<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>azure on my tech ramblings</title>
    
    
    
    <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/tags/azure/</link>
    <description>Recent content in azure on my tech ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 10:03:31 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.mytechramblings.com/tags/azure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Q&amp;A app capable of answering questions related to your enterprise documents using Azure OpenAI&#39;s GPT-4, Pinecone and Streamlit.</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/building-qa-app-with-openai-pinecone-and-streamlit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 10:03:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/building-qa-app-with-openai-pinecone-and-streamlit/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          The purpose of this post is to show you how to build a basic GPT-4 Q&amp;A app in just a couple of hours that is capable of answering questions about your company&#39;s internal documents. We will use Azure OpenAI, Pinecone and Streamlit to build it.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a serverless API that tweets about my blog posts using Azure OpenAI and LangChain</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/build-an-api-that-tweets-using-azure-openai-and-langchain/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 10:01:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/build-an-api-that-tweets-using-azure-openai-and-langchain/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          This post is going to show you a simple way of building a serverless Python API that uses LangChain and Azure OpenAI to create tweets summarizing the content of my blog posts.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to automatically purge stale images from Azure Container Registry using ACR Tasks</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/automatically-purge-acr-images-using-acr-tasks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2022 13:03:19 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/automatically-purge-acr-images-using-acr-tasks/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Keeping your container registry free of stale or unwanted images is a task that often gets overlooked when beginning working with containers in the enterprise. In this post, I want to show you how you can use ACR Tasks to automate this process when working with Azure Container Registry.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying out the built-in container support for the .NET SDK</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/trying-out-the-built-in-container-support-for-the-dotnet-7-sdk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 10:01:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/trying-out-the-built-in-container-support-for-the-dotnet-7-sdk/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          A few months ago the built-in container support for the .NET SDK was announced. In this post I&#39;ll put this feature to test, I&#39;ll try to migrate from an application that contains a rather complex Dockerfile to a new version that has no Dockerfile and instead uses the container support feature.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to deploy an Azure resource using Terraform when it is not available in the AzureRM official provider</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/deploy-az-resources-when-not-available-on-azurerm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 10:30:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/deploy-az-resources-when-not-available-on-azurerm/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          This post is going to walk you through the options available when we want to create or update a service on Azure using Terraform, but it is not available on the AzureRM Terraform provider.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing Azure Private Endpoints DNS resolution over an Azure P2S VPN connection</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/testing-private-dns-resolution-over-a-p2s-vpn-using-azure-dns-private-resolver/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 10:10:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/testing-private-dns-resolution-over-a-p2s-vpn-using-azure-dns-private-resolver/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          The purpose of this post is to try out the new Azure DNS Private Resolver resource. To test it, we&#39;re going to try to solve one of the current issues that Azure VPN has right now: when connected over an Azure P2S VPN the private DNS zone resolution does not work. This becomes quite problematic when you&#39;re using private endpoints to secure some private resources, because there is no easy way to resolve the private endpoint DNS when connected to a P2S VPN.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to bootstrap Terraform and Azure DevOps to start deploying your infrastructure as code to Azure</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/how-to-bootstrap-terraform-and-azdo-to-start-deploying-iac-to-azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 12:30:10 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/how-to-bootstrap-terraform-and-azdo-to-start-deploying-iac-to-azure/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Deploying infrastructure as code on Azure using Azure Pipelines and Terraform requires a minimal bootstrap process. This process can be done manually, but you&#39;ll have to do it every time you want to start deploying resources into a new subscription. So, having some kind of automation seems the way to go here. And that&#39;s exactly what I want to show in this post, how to programmatically bootstrap an Azure subscription and an Azure DevOps project to start deploying Infrastructure as Code with Terraform.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building an Async HTTP Api with Azure Durable Functions and Python</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/building-an-async-http-api-with-durable-functions-and-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 11:20:04 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/building-an-async-http-api-with-durable-functions-and-python/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          The async HTTP API pattern addresses the problem of coordinating the state of long-running operations with external clients. Azure Durable Functions provides built-in support for this pattern and in this post I&#39;m going to show you how to implement it using Python.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing how to use some container vulnerabilities scanners with Azure Pipelines</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/testing-container-vulnerabilities-scanners-using-azure-pipelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 10:45:14 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/testing-container-vulnerabilities-scanners-using-azure-pipelines/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Vulnerability scanning allows us to review the security state of the container images and take actions to fix issues identified during the scan, resulting in more secure deployments. In this post I will be covering how you can use some of the most well-known scanners alongside with your Azure DevOps CI/CD YAML Pipelines.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Securing a graphQL API with Azure Active Directory</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/securing-dotnet-graphql-api-with-aad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 10:21:33 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/securing-dotnet-graphql-api-with-aad/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          In today&#39;s post I want to talk about how you can secure a .NET graphQL API that uses HotChocolate (https://chillicream.com/) with Azure Active Directory.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying to setup an Azure DevOps organization using Terraform</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/automate-azure-devops-setup-using-terraform/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 10:00:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/automate-azure-devops-setup-using-terraform/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          On today&#39;s post I want to test the Azure DevOps Terraform provider and that&#39;s why I&#39;ll be trying to automate the setup of an Azure DevOps organization using it.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing out the Azure Static Web Apps service. Let&#39;s try to deploy this blog into an static web app</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/moving-this-blog-to-azure-static-webapps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 10:04:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/moving-this-blog-to-azure-static-webapps/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          I been wanting to try Azure Static Web Apps for quite some time and I thought that instead of deploying some dummy static site I could use my blog as a test subject, so let&#39;s do it!
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An opinionated approach about how to create an AWS ECS Fargate cluster and deploy apps on it using Azure DevOps Pipelines</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/create-an-ecs-cluster-and-deploy-apps-using-azure-devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 10:10:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/create-an-ecs-cluster-and-deploy-apps-using-azure-devops/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          These past couple of weeks I&#39;ve been tinkering with AWS ECS Fargate and after losing some time tackling different approaches I thought it might be useful to write down what I ended up building, so without further ado let&#39;s dig in.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Answering some basic questions about registering applications on Azure Active Directory</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/answering-basic-questions-about-aad-app-registrations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 10:00:50 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/answering-basic-questions-about-aad-app-registrations/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          These past years I worked with a few companies that uses Azure Active Directory to perform authentication and authorization on their line-of-business (LOB) applications and from time to time I get questions about how to register apps on AAD. Those questions are always pretty similar and most of the time the problem lies in some misconception, so I thought it might be a good idea to try to answer some of them and at the same time write them down in this post.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Provisioning resources on AWS using AWS CDK and Azure DevOps Pipelines</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/provisioning-aws-resources-using-cdk-azure-devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 10:02:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/provisioning-aws-resources-using-cdk-azure-devops/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          In today&#39;s post I will show you how you can deploy an AWS CDK application using Azure DevOps.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A practical example of GitOps using Azure DevOps, Azure Container Registry, Helm, Flux and Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/gitops-with-azure-devops-helm-acr-flux-and-k8s/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 22:10:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/gitops-with-azure-devops-helm-acr-flux-and-k8s/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          GitOps is a way of implementing Continuous Deployment. The core idea of GitOps is having a Git repository that always contains declarative descriptions of the desired infrastructure, and in this post I&#39;ll be building a practical example of GitOps using Azure.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying to automate Azure Active Directory App Registration process using Terraform</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/automate-azure-ad-app-registration-using-terraform/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 21:22:44 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/automate-azure-ad-app-registration-using-terraform/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Today I want to try to use Terraform to automate the app registration process in Azure Active Directory.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why and how you should add a healthcheck endpoint to your Wcf legacy applications</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/how-to-add-healthchecks-to-wcf-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 17:30:06 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/how-to-add-healthchecks-to-wcf-apps/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          What I wanted to talk in these post is how easy is to add a healthcheck endpoint in a WCF application, and how you can use it in case you want to move the application into the Cloud in the near future.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>