<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws on my tech ramblings</title>
    
    
    
    <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/tags/aws/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws on my tech ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 22:00:30 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.mytechramblings.com/tags/aws/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Building and deploying a .NET 8 App on an ARM64 processor using Azure Pipelines and AWS ECS Fargate. Part 1: How to build multi-platform images</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/building-and-deploying-a-dotnet-app-on-arm64-part1-cross-compilation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 22:00:30 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/building-and-deploying-a-dotnet-app-on-arm64-part1-cross-compilation/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          In this two-part series, I’m going to show you how to build and deploy a .NET 8 app container image that targets an ARM64 processor. In part 1, I’ll be discussing some key concepts that you should know about how to build .NET multi-platform images.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Q&amp;A app capable of answering questions related to your enterprise documents using AWS Bedrock, AWS Kendra, AWS S3 and Streamlit</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/building-qa-app-with-aws-bedrock-kendra-s3-and-streamlit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 10:00:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/building-qa-app-with-aws-bedrock-kendra-s3-and-streamlit/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          The purpose of this post is to demonstrate how easy is to build a basic Q&amp;A app capable of answering questions about your company&#39;s internal documents. This time, we will use only AWS services to build it (plus Streamlit for the user interface).
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 ways to deploy a .NET Lambda using AWS CDK</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/deploy-dotnet-lambdas-with-aws-cdk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 10:01:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/deploy-dotnet-lambdas-with-aws-cdk/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          This post is going to walk you through 5 different ways to deploy a .NET lambda using AWS CDK.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying out the built-in container support for the .NET SDK</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/trying-out-the-built-in-container-support-for-the-dotnet-7-sdk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 10:01:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/trying-out-the-built-in-container-support-for-the-dotnet-7-sdk/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          A few months ago the built-in container support for the .NET SDK was announced. In this post I&#39;ll put this feature to test, I&#39;ll try to migrate from an application that contains a rather complex Dockerfile to a new version that has no Dockerfile and instead uses the container support feature.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to notify AWS events to Microsoft Teams using AWS EventBridge and AWS Lambda</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/notify-aws-events-to-microsoft-teams/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 10:01:12 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/notify-aws-events-to-microsoft-teams/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          An AWS event indicates a change in a service, and in this post I want to show you how you can notify those events to a Microsoft Teams channel using AWS EventBridge and AWS Lambda.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keep your .NET platform images up to date using AWS ECR and Azure Pipelines</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/keep-your-platform-images-updated-when-using-aws-ecr-with-azure-pipelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 11:06:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/keep-your-platform-images-updated-when-using-aws-ecr-with-azure-pipelines/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          When talking about containers security on the enterprise one of the best practices is to use your own platform images, those platform images are the base for your company applications. In this post I&#39;m going to show you an opinionated implementation of how to automate the creation and update of your own .NET platform images using Azure Pipelines and AWS ECR.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to deploy a SignalR Core application to AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/deploying-a-signalr-core-app-on-aws/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 10:00:40 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/deploying-a-signalr-core-app-on-aws/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          This post is about which AWS services can be used and how to set them up properly when you want to deploy a SignalR Core application to AWS.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Profiling a .NET6 app running on AWS ECS Fargate with dotnet-monitor</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/profiling-a-net-app-on-aws-ecs-fargate-with-dotnet-monitor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 10:25:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/profiling-a-net-app-on-aws-ecs-fargate-with-dotnet-monitor/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          The dotnet-monitor tool is an alternative to the .NET CLI diagnostic tools. In this post I&#39;ll show you how to deploy a .NET 6 application into AWS ECS Fargate with dotnet-monitor as a sidecar container, and afterwards how you can profile an app using the dotnet-monitor HTTP API.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with AWS Distro for OpenTelemetry and distributed tracing using .NET. Part 2: Building the demo</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/getting-started-with-aws-distro-for-otel-and-dotnet-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 10:00:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/getting-started-with-aws-distro-for-otel-and-dotnet-part-2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          This is a 2 part-series post. In part 2 I’ll show you how to build and configure properly a few distributed .NET apps that will send traces to the AWS OTEL Collector, and also how to analyze those traces in AWS X-Ray.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with AWS Distro for OpenTelemetry and distributed tracing using .NET. Part 1: Setting up the AWS OTEL Collector</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/getting-started-with-aws-distro-for-otel-and-dotnet-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 10:10:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/getting-started-with-aws-distro-for-otel-and-dotnet-part-1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          This is a 2 part-series post. In part 1 I’ll be talking about what is the AWS OpenTelemetry Collector and how to set it up for ingesting and exporting traces to AWS X-Ray.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing how to use some container vulnerabilities scanners with Azure Pipelines</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/testing-container-vulnerabilities-scanners-using-azure-pipelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 10:45:14 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/testing-container-vulnerabilities-scanners-using-azure-pipelines/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Vulnerability scanning allows us to review the security state of the container images and take actions to fix issues identified during the scan, resulting in more secure deployments. In this post I will be covering how you can use some of the most well-known scanners alongside with your Azure DevOps CI/CD YAML Pipelines.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some common gotchas when trying to deploy a dotnet gRPC app to AWS ECS</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/some-gotchas-when-deploying-a-dotnet-grpc-app-to-ecs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 10:05:32 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/some-gotchas-when-deploying-a-dotnet-grpc-app-to-ecs/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Lately I&#39;ve been deploying a sizable amount of gRPC services to AWS ECS so I thought it might be useful to talk a little bit about some gotchas I have encountered. Some of the problems I&#39;ll be talking about on this post are specific of the .NET implementation of gRPC and another ones are from the AWS side.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An opinionated approach about how to create an AWS ECS Fargate cluster and deploy apps on it using Azure DevOps Pipelines</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/create-an-ecs-cluster-and-deploy-apps-using-azure-devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 10:10:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/create-an-ecs-cluster-and-deploy-apps-using-azure-devops/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          These past couple of weeks I&#39;ve been tinkering with AWS ECS Fargate and after losing some time tackling different approaches I thought it might be useful to write down what I ended up building, so without further ado let&#39;s dig in.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Provisioning resources on AWS using AWS CDK and Azure DevOps Pipelines</title>
      <link>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/provisioning-aws-resources-using-cdk-azure-devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 10:02:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/provisioning-aws-resources-using-cdk-azure-devops/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          In today&#39;s post I will show you how you can deploy an AWS CDK application using Azure DevOps.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>